<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Chicken on Jerry's Recipes</title><link>https://food.jerryluce.xyz/tags/chicken/</link><description>Recent content in Chicken on Jerry's Recipes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://food.jerryluce.xyz/tags/chicken/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tuscan Chicken</title><link>https://food.jerryluce.xyz/p/tuscan-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://food.jerryluce.xyz/p/tuscan-chicken/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://food.jerryluce.xyz/p/tuscan-chicken/Chicken.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Tuscan Chicken" />&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="chicken">Chicken&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 tbsp. Extra-Virgin Olive Oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 Boneless Skinless Grass-Finished Chicken Breasts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pink Himalayan Salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Freshly Ground Black Pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Freshly Ground White Pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="sauce">Sauce&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1/2 tbsp. Fresh Oregano&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 tbsp. Fresh Basil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 tbsp. Grass-Finished Butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 Cloves Garlic, Minced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 Shallots, Finely Chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 1/2 c. Cherry Tomatoes, Halved&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 c. Baby Spinach&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 c. Heavy Cream&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3/4 c. Chardonnay&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 tbsp. Chicken Demi-Glaze&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 c. Freshly Grated Parmesan&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lemon Wedges, for Serving&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Season the chicken with salt and pepper and let it rest for an hour. This helps to enhance the flavor of the chicken.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heat some oil in a cast-iron skillet over medium heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the seasoned chicken to the skillet and cook it until it reaches an internal temperature of 165°F. This should take about 6 minutes per side. Ensure the chicken is cooked through and not pink in the center.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove the cooked chicken from the skillet and set it aside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lower the heat to low-medium and add minced garlic, chopped shallots, diced tomatoes, and butter to the skillet. Cook these ingredients until they become tender and fragrant.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deglaze the pan by adding Chardonnay (white wine) and then adding demi-glaze. Deglazing helps to release the flavorful browned bits from the bottom of the pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reduce the liquid in the skillet to about half its volume. This step concentrates the flavors.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add spinach to the skillet and simmer it until it wilts. This should only take a few minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stir in heavy cream and grated Parmesan cheese. This will create a creamy and cheesy sauce.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Incorporate oregano and basil into the sauce. These herbs will add a nice aroma and flavor to the dish.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Return the cooked chicken to the pan and simmer the mixture on low heat. Stir vigorously for about 5 minutes, allowing the chicken to absorb the flavors of the sauce.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve the chicken dish, garnishing it with lemon, and season it to taste. The lemon adds a refreshing citrus note to the dish.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>