<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Other on Jerry's Recipes</title><link>https://food.jerryluce.xyz/categories/other/</link><description>Recent content in Other on Jerry's Recipes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://food.jerryluce.xyz/categories/other/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Brown Stock</title><link>https://food.jerryluce.xyz/p/brown-stock/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://food.jerryluce.xyz/p/brown-stock/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 kg Beef and Veal Pieces (knuckles, chin, or suitable stewing cuts)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Small Ham Knuckle&lt;/li>
&lt;li>150 g (5.3 oz) Blanched Fresh Pork Rind&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2.5 kg Beef Bones, Chopped into Chunks (ask your butcher for assistance)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>150 g (5.3 oz) Roughly Diced Carrots&lt;/li>
&lt;li>150 g (5.3 oz) Roughly Diced Onions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5 Fresh Parsley Stalks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Sprigs of Thyme&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Whole, Fresh Bay Leaf&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Clove of Garlic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 Liters (16.5 cups) of Water (plus an additional 1 liter / 4 cups for topping up during the simmering process)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="part-1">Part 1&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Debone the meats and break the bones into small chunks. Roast them in a hot oven until they achieve a dark brown color.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create a bouquet garni by tying together parsley, thyme, and bay leaf with a piece of string.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>After roasting, add carrots and onions to the pan with the bones, cooking for 5 minutes to lightly sear the vegetables.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove the pan from the oven and transfer the roasted bones and vegetables to a sieve. Let them drip over a bowl to eliminate excess fat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Transfer the bones and vegetables to a large stockpot. Add a bouquet garni and garlic, then fill with cold water until it&amp;rsquo;s a few centimeters above the bones.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bring to a boil, skim the scum from the surface, then reduce the heat and simmer on very low heat for 5 to 6 hours. Maintain the liquid level by adding water as needed and continue skimming impurities.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="part-2">Part 2&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Cut the meat into large cubes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a separate large stockpot or saucepan, add a small amount of oil. Sear the meat pieces until they achieve a light brown color.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pour the equivalent of a glass of the previously prepared bone broth over the seared meat. Let it reduce on medium heat until the liquid almost evaporates to a syrupy glaze. Repeat this process two or three times.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>After the third deglazing, add the remaining bone broth to the pot and bring it to a boil. Skim off any impurities from the surface and then let it simmer for approximately 2 hours to extract flavors from the meat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Turn off the heat after 2 hours and let the stock rest for at least 30 minutes. Pass it through a fine mesh sieve into a clean glass container. For further refinement, perform a second filtering using cheesecloth.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Allow the stock to cool at room temperature and refrigerate overnight.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once the stock has cooled, a solid fat layer will form at the surface. Easily scoop it out for other uses.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>