<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sauces on Jerry's Recipes</title><link>https://food.jerryluce.xyz/categories/sauces/</link><description>Recent content in Sauces on Jerry's Recipes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://food.jerryluce.xyz/categories/sauces/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bordelaise</title><link>https://food.jerryluce.xyz/p/bordelaise/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://food.jerryluce.xyz/p/bordelaise/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="reduction">Reduction&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>250 g Espagnole&lt;/li>
&lt;li>40 g Shallots&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 g Cracked Peppercorns, Mignonette&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Sprig Thyme&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Bay Leaf&lt;/li>
&lt;li>250 g Red Wine&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="sauce">Sauce&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>40 g Grass-Finished Bone Marrow, poached&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Few Drops of Lemon Juice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salt and Freshly Ground Black Pepper, to taste&lt;/li>
&lt;li>10 g Cold Grass-Finished Butter&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Place all the reduction ingredients into a saucepan and place it over medium heat. Reduce by 4/5ths. add the brown sauce, and cook for 10 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pass the sauce through a chinois and add salt and lemon juice; the lemon is used to accentuate the flavors, but it should not dominate.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bring to a simmer, remove from heat, and gently stir in the butter a little at a time (monte au beurre).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Poach the marrow by plunging it into lightly simmering salted water. Cook for several seconds and refresh in ice water.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dice the poached marrow and add to the sauce.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Espagnole</title><link>https://food.jerryluce.xyz/p/espagnole/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://food.jerryluce.xyz/p/espagnole/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 Bay Leaf&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 to 4 Sprigs of Fresh Thyme&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 to 4 Fresh Parsley Stems&lt;/li>
&lt;li>7 to 8 Whole Black Peppercorns&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Ounce of Clarified Grass-Finished Butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 Cup of Diced Onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 Cup of Diced Carrot&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 Cup of Diced Celery&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Ounce of All-Purpose Flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 Cups of Brown Stock&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Tablespoons of Tomato Puree&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Collect all the necessary ingredients.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bundle the bay leaf, thyme, parsley stems, and peppercorns in a square of cheesecloth, securing the corners with kitchen twine. Ensure one string is long enough to tie to the pot handle for easy retrieval.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a sturdy medium saucepan, melt butter over medium heat until it turns frothy.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the mirepoix—onions, carrots, and celery—and sauté until lightly browned, approximately 6 minutes, avoiding burning.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Gradually stir flour into the mirepoix with a wooden spoon, creating a thick paste known as roux.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reduce heat to low and cook the roux until it lightly browns, around 4 to 5 minutes, without letting it burn.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Slowly whisk in the stock and tomato purée, ensuring a lump-free mixture.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bring the mixture to a boil, then reduce heat to low, and introduce the sachet. Simmer until the volume reduces by 1/3 (resulting in about 2 cups), stirring often to prevent scorching, for 35 to 45 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use a ladle to skim off any impurities that surface.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove the sauce from heat, discard the sachet.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For a smoother consistency, carefully strain the sauce through a wire mesh strainer lined with cheesecloth.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Keep the sauce covered and warm until ready to use. If not using immediately, cool it completely and store in an airtight container in the refrigerator for up to 5 days.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>