<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Jerry's Recipes</title><link>https://food.jerryluce.xyz/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Jerry's Recipes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://food.jerryluce.xyz/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bordelaise</title><link>https://food.jerryluce.xyz/p/bordelaise/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://food.jerryluce.xyz/p/bordelaise/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="reduction">Reduction&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>250 g Espagnole&lt;/li>
&lt;li>40 g Shallots&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 g Cracked Peppercorns, Mignonette&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Sprig Thyme&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Bay Leaf&lt;/li>
&lt;li>250 g Red Wine&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="sauce">Sauce&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>40 g Grass-Finished Bone Marrow, poached&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Few Drops of Lemon Juice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salt and Freshly Ground Black Pepper, to taste&lt;/li>
&lt;li>10 g Cold Grass-Finished Butter&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Place all the reduction ingredients into a saucepan and place it over medium heat. Reduce by 4/5ths. add the brown sauce, and cook for 10 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pass the sauce through a chinois and add salt and lemon juice; the lemon is used to accentuate the flavors, but it should not dominate.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bring to a simmer, remove from heat, and gently stir in the butter a little at a time (monte au beurre).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Poach the marrow by plunging it into lightly simmering salted water. Cook for several seconds and refresh in ice water.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Dice the poached marrow and add to the sauce.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Brown Stock</title><link>https://food.jerryluce.xyz/p/brown-stock/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://food.jerryluce.xyz/p/brown-stock/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 kg Beef and Veal Pieces (knuckles, chin, or suitable stewing cuts)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Small Ham Knuckle&lt;/li>
&lt;li>150 g (5.3 oz) Blanched Fresh Pork Rind&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2.5 kg Beef Bones, Chopped into Chunks (ask your butcher for assistance)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>150 g (5.3 oz) Roughly Diced Carrots&lt;/li>
&lt;li>150 g (5.3 oz) Roughly Diced Onions&lt;/li>
&lt;li>5 Fresh Parsley Stalks&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Sprigs of Thyme&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Whole, Fresh Bay Leaf&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Clove of Garlic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 Liters (16.5 cups) of Water (plus an additional 1 liter / 4 cups for topping up during the simmering process)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="part-1">Part 1&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Debone the meats and break the bones into small chunks. Roast them in a hot oven until they achieve a dark brown color.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create a bouquet garni by tying together parsley, thyme, and bay leaf with a piece of string.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>After roasting, add carrots and onions to the pan with the bones, cooking for 5 minutes to lightly sear the vegetables.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove the pan from the oven and transfer the roasted bones and vegetables to a sieve. Let them drip over a bowl to eliminate excess fat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Transfer the bones and vegetables to a large stockpot. Add a bouquet garni and garlic, then fill with cold water until it&amp;rsquo;s a few centimeters above the bones.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bring to a boil, skim the scum from the surface, then reduce the heat and simmer on very low heat for 5 to 6 hours. Maintain the liquid level by adding water as needed and continue skimming impurities.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h3 id="part-2">Part 2&lt;/h3>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Cut the meat into large cubes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a separate large stockpot or saucepan, add a small amount of oil. Sear the meat pieces until they achieve a light brown color.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pour the equivalent of a glass of the previously prepared bone broth over the seared meat. Let it reduce on medium heat until the liquid almost evaporates to a syrupy glaze. Repeat this process two or three times.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>After the third deglazing, add the remaining bone broth to the pot and bring it to a boil. Skim off any impurities from the surface and then let it simmer for approximately 2 hours to extract flavors from the meat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Turn off the heat after 2 hours and let the stock rest for at least 30 minutes. Pass it through a fine mesh sieve into a clean glass container. For further refinement, perform a second filtering using cheesecloth.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Allow the stock to cool at room temperature and refrigerate overnight.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Once the stock has cooled, a solid fat layer will form at the surface. Easily scoop it out for other uses.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Espagnole</title><link>https://food.jerryluce.xyz/p/espagnole/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://food.jerryluce.xyz/p/espagnole/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 Bay Leaf&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 to 4 Sprigs of Fresh Thyme&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 to 4 Fresh Parsley Stems&lt;/li>
&lt;li>7 to 8 Whole Black Peppercorns&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Ounce of Clarified Grass-Finished Butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 Cup of Diced Onion&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 Cup of Diced Carrot&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 Cup of Diced Celery&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Ounce of All-Purpose Flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 Cups of Brown Stock&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 Tablespoons of Tomato Puree&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Collect all the necessary ingredients.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bundle the bay leaf, thyme, parsley stems, and peppercorns in a square of cheesecloth, securing the corners with kitchen twine. Ensure one string is long enough to tie to the pot handle for easy retrieval.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a sturdy medium saucepan, melt butter over medium heat until it turns frothy.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the mirepoix—onions, carrots, and celery—and sauté until lightly browned, approximately 6 minutes, avoiding burning.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Gradually stir flour into the mirepoix with a wooden spoon, creating a thick paste known as roux.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reduce heat to low and cook the roux until it lightly browns, around 4 to 5 minutes, without letting it burn.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Slowly whisk in the stock and tomato purée, ensuring a lump-free mixture.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Bring the mixture to a boil, then reduce heat to low, and introduce the sachet. Simmer until the volume reduces by 1/3 (resulting in about 2 cups), stirring often to prevent scorching, for 35 to 45 minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Use a ladle to skim off any impurities that surface.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove the sauce from heat, discard the sachet.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For a smoother consistency, carefully strain the sauce through a wire mesh strainer lined with cheesecloth.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Keep the sauce covered and warm until ready to use. If not using immediately, cool it completely and store in an airtight container in the refrigerator for up to 5 days.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Tuscan Chicken</title><link>https://food.jerryluce.xyz/p/tuscan-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://food.jerryluce.xyz/p/tuscan-chicken/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://food.jerryluce.xyz/p/tuscan-chicken/Chicken.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Tuscan Chicken" />&lt;h2 id="ingredients">Ingredients&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="chicken">Chicken&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1 tbsp. Extra-Virgin Olive Oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>4 Boneless Skinless Grass-Finished Chicken Breasts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pink Himalayan Salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Freshly Ground Black Pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Freshly Ground White Pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="sauce">Sauce&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1/2 tbsp. Fresh Oregano&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 tbsp. Fresh Basil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 tbsp. Grass-Finished Butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 Cloves Garlic, Minced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 Shallots, Finely Chopped&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 1/2 c. Cherry Tomatoes, Halved&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 c. Baby Spinach&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 c. Heavy Cream&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3/4 c. Chardonnay&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 tbsp. Chicken Demi-Glaze&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 c. Freshly Grated Parmesan&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lemon Wedges, for Serving&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="directions">Directions&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Season the chicken with salt and pepper and let it rest for an hour. This helps to enhance the flavor of the chicken.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heat some oil in a cast-iron skillet over medium heat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add the seasoned chicken to the skillet and cook it until it reaches an internal temperature of 165°F. This should take about 6 minutes per side. Ensure the chicken is cooked through and not pink in the center.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove the cooked chicken from the skillet and set it aside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lower the heat to low-medium and add minced garlic, chopped shallots, diced tomatoes, and butter to the skillet. Cook these ingredients until they become tender and fragrant.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Deglaze the pan by adding Chardonnay (white wine) and then adding demi-glaze. Deglazing helps to release the flavorful browned bits from the bottom of the pan.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reduce the liquid in the skillet to about half its volume. This step concentrates the flavors.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add spinach to the skillet and simmer it until it wilts. This should only take a few minutes.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stir in heavy cream and grated Parmesan cheese. This will create a creamy and cheesy sauce.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Incorporate oregano and basil into the sauce. These herbs will add a nice aroma and flavor to the dish.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Return the cooked chicken to the pan and simmer the mixture on low heat. Stir vigorously for about 5 minutes, allowing the chicken to absorb the flavors of the sauce.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve the chicken dish, garnishing it with lemon, and season it to taste. The lemon adds a refreshing citrus note to the dish.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>